Tufts Observer UP055
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Tufts Observer, 1996 -- 2000; UP055.025; 1.2 Linear Feet
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-04-23; UP055.025.025.00033 (Box 25)
    Additional user copy in the Reading Room. Construction for New Fieldhouse Underway in Fall. Senate Recesses After Year of Active Debate. Clinic Escorts Face Protests. Tufts Searches to Fill Affirmative Action Job. [Jack] Schnirman Wins Presidency. Debate Still Surrounds Tufts Men Against Violence Pledge Not to Rape. Student's Work Benefits Campus [Jackie Okin]. Lights, Camera, Action, Roll Film. The Year in Review: 1997-1998 The Year's Campus Awakenings Tufts Faces a Year of Strong Student Activism, Protest, New Challenges. Crew Gets Warmup. Athlete of the Week: Robin Zimmerly. Hangin' Tough [Softball]. Women Setting Pace for Upcoming NESCACs [Track]. Jumbos [baseball] End Six-Game Skid. Serving Up a Three-Match Win Streak [Men's Tennis]. Women's Lacrosse Heading For Home. Men's Track Takes Second. Nothing New For Men's Lacrosse. Hub Fans Bid Wise Adieu.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-09-03; UP055.025.025.00034 (Box 25)
    Bright Minds, Bright Skies Converge. Tufts Alum [Bill Richardson] Tackles Double Diplomacy. Commuting Transfers Adjust to New Policy. Nobel Recipient's [Allan MacLeod Cormack] Life-Saving Legacy. TCU [Tufts Community Union] President [Jack Schnirman] Welcomes the Class of 2002. Tufts Returns Several Top Athletes. Run-In Makes [Jason] Burke Stronger. The Elephant, the Myth, the Legend.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-09-10; UP055.025.025.00035 (Box 25)
    Sigma Nu Revokes Ban, Fraternity Not Going Dry. Career Planning Center Relocates. Costly Patio Construction Opens Up Mixed Reviews. Senator George Mitchell To Speak at Tufts. Construction Plans Underway On Campus. Lessons Learned During Storytime. TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senators Pioneer Boston-Area College Consortium. [Director of Athletics Rocko] Carzo Names Alumnus [Brian Murphy] Hockey Coach. Jumbos Presented Postseason Awards. Track Stars Place Second At Nationals. Tufts Sets Sail on New Season. Baseball and Softball Players Win Honors.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-09-17; UP055.025.025.00036 (Box 25)
    Tufts Upgrades Computer Capabilities. Expanded Handbook Outlines Revised Disciplinary Policies. [Tufts Community Union] Senate Seeks Amelioration of Budget Concerns. Fall Fest Leads to Negative Publicity. Guiding Students Through Research. Blueberries May Hold Key to Youth. Tufts wins AIDS Grant. Optical Nose at Forefront of Sensation Experimentation. Documentary on Chinese Jews Premieres. Women [cross country] Seek Breakthrough Season. [Rod] Hemingway Returns for One Last Run [women's cross country]. Optimistic Start for Women's Volleyball. [Matt] Adler Leads the Jumbo Charge [men's soccer]. Women [soccer] Kick Off to a Good Start. Youth to Revitalize Women's Tennis. 'Crews'ing Toward Head of the Charles. Sailors Hope to Improve on Last Year's Record. Jumbos [field hockey] Open With Two Home Wins.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-09-24; UP055.025.025.00037 (Box 25)
    Visa Cap Shuts Out Economics Professor [Edward Kutsoati]. Tufts Reacts to the Clinton Sex Scandal. International Community Voices Opinions About American Leaders' Morals. [Tufts Community Union] Senators Discuss Fundraising Projects, Study Abroad At Sunday Meeting. Conquering the Airwaves and Beyond. Jewish Community Welcomes New Year. Student Organizations Risk Funding. [Jerry] Karacz and [Dan] Morse to Lead [football] Team. [Football] Starters Return for Run in '98. Tufts [football] Faces Tough Games in NESCAC [New England Small College Athletic Conference]. Jumbo [football] Stampede! Jumbos Sports Kicks Off Season. Late Season [football] Momentum To Help This Year's Squad.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-10-01; UP055.025.025.00038 (Box 25)
    Communication Vital For Campus Improvement. Student Forum Gives Way to Open Discussion. Students Organize Forum, Make Efforts To Influence, Implement Social Change. Women's Studies Major Moves Ahead. Professor [Shuk-Mei Ho] Conducts Revolutionary Research on Prostate Cancer. [Tufts Community Union] Senate Overestimates Budget Surplus. Optimus Prime Opens Up Poetic Community. [Cindy] Pollard Courting the Press. Career Planning Center Expands Services. Nobel Prize Winner [Dr. Jose Ramos-Horta] to Lecture. Bars to Close Early. [Steve] McDermid Big in Wins [men's soccer]. Doubles Holds Key to Jumbo Success [women's tennis]. Field Hockey Races Out to 5-0 Start. [Women's] Soccer Ranked Number One in New England. Jumbos [football] Trample Hamilton. Former Student [Nick Trotman] Wins World [sailing] Title.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-10-08; UP055.025.025.00039 (Box 25)
    Tufts' Hiroshima, Nagasaki Exhibit Largest in America. Professors, Alumni Recount Racial Tension. EPIIC [Education for Public Inquiry and International Citizenship] Students Return From Annual Retreat. [Chris] Rogers Wins Top Honor For Excellence in Undergraduate Teaching. English Society Awaits Senate Recognition, Funding. Lounge Cable Severed, Senate Weighs Cut. Student [Ohene Asare] Pursues Change at Tufts. German Band [Die Sterne] to Play. Learning Diversity Essential. Catching Up with [football] Coach [Bill] Samko. Women's Crew Starts Season Off On Good Note. Tufts Coed Sailing Team Ranked First in Nation, Women Third. Golfers in the Swing of Things at NESCACs [New England Small College Athletic Conference]. Varsity [Crew] Men Stroke Way to Victory at Textile Regatta. Two Up, Two Down For Volleyball Team. [Lynn] Cooper Scores Twice in [women's soccer] Win. Men's Soccer Loses Heartbreaker to Bates. Jumbos [football] Master Bates. Men's Cross Country Team Wins Tufts Invitational. Field Hockey Team Stays Perfect at 6-0.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-10-15; UP055.025.025.00040 (Box 25)
    Coming Out Day Tries for Increased Awareness. New International Letters and Visual Studies Major Created. Students Urged to Take Bite Out of Crime. [Jack] Schnirman Announces Plans to Strengthen Campus Traditions At Sunday Senate Meeting. Giving South Asians A Voice. Senate to Remedy ID Problems at 'Scrape Nights.' 'Crews' Down to the Head of the Charles. Crew Fares Well in Poor Weather. Volleyball Splits at Bowdoin Invite. Harriers Looking Good for New Englands. Boston Curse Ends as Jumbos [football] Move to 3-0. Women [field hockey] Stay Unbeaten. Best Start in 20 Years [women's soccer] Marred by 2-1 Loss. [Bowdoin] Polar Bears Outlast Jumbos [men's soccer] In Battle of Seventh Ranked. Tufts [sailing] Dominates New England Singlehanded.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-10-22; UP055.025.025.00041 (Box 25)
    [Iris] Chang To Lecture on Chinese Holocaust. TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senate Temporarily Closes Buffer Funding. Pop Band Fastball Will Play Fall Rock Show. Writer Haruki Murakami Shares His Thoughts With Students. Student Services Inititative Seeks To Provide Online Course Registration. Professor [Lee] Edelman Takes Leave of Absence, Chairs English Department at SUNY. Former Graduate Student [David] O'Brien Passes Away. Making It A Year To Remember. Internship Office Established for Engineers. History Department Undergoes Internal Review. Tufts Honors Gold Medal Hockey Coach [Ben Smith]. Water Polo Team Splashes Onto the Scene. More Sailors Head to Nationals. Jumbos [field hockey] Lose First of Year, Still Move Up in Rankings. Tennis Making Some Racket. Crew Ends Season on the Charles. Cross Country Teams Place Well At New Englands. [Bill] Samko's [football] Squad Sinks Trinity, Stays Unbeaten. Men's Soccer Engineers Decisive Win Against MIT. Volleyball Upsets Amherst at Quad. Women's Soccer Back on Track.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-10-29; UP055.025.025.00042 (Box 25)
    Performance Groups Feel Pinch of Inadequate Facilities. Faculty Cautiously Supports Tenure Process. Black Solidarity Day Kicks Off Nov. 2 With Rally, Speakers. Revered Professor [Morse Hamilton] Dead at 55. TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senate Reaches Out With Web Site, Tufts Polls. Studying Culture in Child Development. Attack Shocks Campus. Novice Row to Head of Class at Last Regatta. Volleyball Places Fourth At Hall of Fame Classic. 'Lyons' Strength Leads to Victory in [men's] Cross Country. Clear Skies, Cloudy Performances. Gawlak's Goals Give Field Hockey Lone Win. Women [soccer] Poised To Gain NCAA Bid.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-11-05; UP055.025.025.00043 (Box 25)
    Grant seekers complain of neglect. Senator [George Mitchell] affirms hope for peace. Socialists of Tufts unite. Generation stress: struggling to manage university pressures. [Dean John] Galvin applies years of military experience to Fletcher development. Extremists target abortion doctors [Dr. Barnett Slepian]. University chaplain [Rev. Scotty Mclennan] reflects on switching religions. Housing crunch sticks it to students. Runners entering NCAA qualifiers on right foot. Fencing 101. Gut-check time as men's soccer travels to Middlebury. Ladies first: women's soccer team wins at Amherst, clinches first ever NCAA bid. Field hockey strokes its way into NCAA tournament. [Women's] volleyball prepares for NESCAC's.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-11-12; UP055.025.025.00044 (Box 25)
    Board [of Trustees] rejects senate's junior trustee program. Students, restaurants question success of merchants on points. Hotung plans for more inviting atmosphere. Student Organizations criticize ALBO's [Allocations Board] behavior. Telefund solicits University donations. [Senior Shadi Tayarani] making a difference on and off the stage. Jumbos look to did up trouble at ECACs. Swimmers push off winter sports season with preseason meet. Tufts [field hockey] chance to win NCAA's 'Rowan'ed in first round. Freshman Lynn Cooper's three goals send Tufts [women's soccer] to NCAA quarterfinals. Jumbo win sends men [soccer] to ECACs. Seniors bid Ellis adieu, beat Colby [football]. Second sevens prove cross country's depth.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-11-19; UP055.025.025.00045 (Box 25)
    African-American stats spark debate. [President] DiBiaggio proposes college of public service. Anti-gay graffiti shocks Miller Hall. Somerville seeks volunteers to clean up neighborhood. Student advisory committee to address shuttle service, parking, registration issues. [Associate Chaplain David] O'Leary guides students on spiritual quest. Tufts Feminist Alliance ptotests welfare legislation. Italian artist [Carol Rama] mounts Boston exhibition. Tough end to a long year [men's soccer]. What a long, strange kick it's been. Jumbo's volleyball loses to Geneseo in ECAC quarterfinals. Men [cross country] step into NCAA spotlight. A historic season ends [football]. Ithaca halts Tufts' [women's soccer] amazing run in quarterfinals.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-12-03; UP055.025.025.00046 (Box 25)
    Students berate forum panel of administrators. Republicans struggle on liberal campus. Student disciplined for racial harassment. Soapbox may encourage student voice. Lifetime e-mail for alumni proposed. True liberal artist [Cal Levis] finds many strateges. Liberal arts education a business success. The world's most fun summer job [conference bureau]. President [John DiBaggio] strives for broad diversity. Hockey gears up for strong season. Sailors place at nationals.
  - Tufts Observer, 1998-12-10; UP055.025.025.00047 (Box 25)
    Black community confronts administrators. TCU [Tufts Community Union] Treasurer [Larry] Harris' e-mail questions cash value of Tufts. Res. Life to renovate Latin Way. Pancake pub tries for new flip. Tufts signs name to alcohol treaty. Pan-African alliance's moral statement of purpose. Men's basketball team deprives the pride. Hockey bounces back from loss to St. Michael's. Lady Jumbos [basketball] bring late-game surges.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-01-28; UP055.025.025.00048 (Box 25)
    Computer science enrollment rises sharply. George Davis named director of African American Center. [Vice President for Arts, Sciences, and Technology I. Melvin] Bernstein responds to diversity protests. Library creates [Joseph E.] Gonzalez endowment. Worldly scholar [Ina Baghdiantz McCabe] investigates silk trade. The world made real by one vacation. Reaching new depth in the water. [Junior Molly] Baker burns Cougars in victory [women's basketball]. Jumbo hockey feels mid-season heat. Men's basketball looks to put away winter skids.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-02-04; UP055.025.025.00049 (Box 25)
    [I. Melvin] Bernstein pledges millions to match Tufts' competitors. First two [minority] forums address admissions, financial aid. Student's rumors site attracts attention. Engineers to compete in national bridge contest. Greg Czarnecki brings asian travel experiences to new Tufts position. Promoting diversity or playing favorites? Peace conference offers answers. [Sophmore Dan] Flaherty leads men's basketball to victory. Men [indoor track] on track for championships. Hockey Pushes for playoffs. Climbing more than the hill.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-02-11; UP055.025.025.00050 (Box 25)
    Physics department contends with few majors, poor facilities. Alumnus [Bernard M. Gordon] donates CAT scan. Abortion advertisement sparks campus controversy. [Tufts Community Union] Senate to debate resolution for Women's Studies major. NOW president [Patricia Ireland] to address issues of diversity at Tufts. Hawaiian [Senior Nicole Takesono] brings hula to the classroom. Massachusetts to establish Honors College. The modern women of Cassatt at the MFA. Equestrian team prevails despite lack of funds. Men's Volleyball spikes its way to a winning streak. Men's basketball lost to Conn. College and Weslyan over the weekend. Ladies end swim season defeating Regis. Boudrow, Broudrow, Golly! Cards deck lady jumbo's [basketball]. Williams leaves swimmers high and dry. Women's track puts in strong race at Bowdoin.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-02-18; UP055.025.025.00051 (Box 25)
    [I. Mervin] Bernstein seeks funds to support initiative. Senate questions policies, quality of dining services. Gloria Anzaldua to speak at Tufts. Romance Languages offers few upper-level courses. Senate rejects $12,000 request from 16mm Conspiracy film club. Professor [Gregory] Crane brings the classics to monitors nationwide with Perseus. Party's over for Dartmouth 'Boys Club'. Club members anticipate International culture week. Women's squash ready for Howe Cup matches. Jumbo's [men's basketball] lose close contests, fall below .500. Women run down division I sprinters. Hockey team earns postseason bid with winning weekend. Jumbo's [men's track] on cruise control at Wesleyan.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-02-25; UP055.025.025.00052 (Box 25)
    University Considers Marketing Tufts' Logo. Symposium Showcases Reseach Achievements. Fate of Club Sports Uncertain After Senate Resolution. Student Activities Coordinators [David Backman and Michaela Murphy] Resign. Graduate Student Council Protests University Neglect. Experienced Volunteer [Tommy Calvert] Pushes His Limits. 1949: University Aides Post-War Europeans. NOW [National Organization for Women] President Patricia Ireland Lectures About Women in Washington. Re'Fleck'tions of the Jazz Show. View the World Upside-Down Through the Lens of [Abelardo] Morell. [Women] Swimmers Take Seventh at Div. IIIs. Women's Basketball Sinking as Season Ends. Men's Basketball Winless Through February. [Men's Track] Postseason Powerhouse. Women Fencers Clinch First at New Englands. Jumbo Hockey Recovers, Looks Sharp vs. [New Hampshire College] Penmen.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-03-11; UP055.025.025.00053 (Box 25)
    Local suspect arrested in connection with hate crime. Perseus project poised to receive $2.7 million grant. Student-faculty committee reverses judiciary ruling. Though illegal, MP3 popular at Tufts. Coming year brings changes to culture houses. [David] Denby challenges the minds of students. Annual EPIIC [Education for Public Inquiry and International Citizenship] symposium concludes, students reflect on experience. A fond farewell to Rocky [Carzo]. Jumbos fall through the ice in postseason [hockey].
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-04-01; UP055.025.025.00054 (Box 25)
    April Fool's edition.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-04-08; UP055.025.025.00055 (Box 25)
    Controversial EPIIC topic postponed by director. Students rally against violence. Tufts admits record numbers. New study abroad in Japan begins. Alumnus [Cornell Coley] returns to teach students the art of Afro-Brazillian dance. Softball team hovers at .500. Sailors to continue national prominence at Friis trophy regata. Jumbos [lacrosse] trample trinity bantams.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-04-15; UP055.025.025.00056 (Box 25)
    Senate considers controversial gay issues. Pan-African alliance officer elections disputed. Trustees form new office of technology transfer. Faculty senate proposal rejected. Noam Chomsly to speak at Tufts. Tufts alum [Jack Fultz] races back to finish line. Dropping the softball. Sailors take second in Friis Trophy Regatta. Runners on pace for qualifiers. Tennis plagued by injuries. Jumbos [baseball] trounce MIT.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-04-22; UP055.025.025.00057 (Box 25)
    [Jack] Schnirman propses presidential cabinet. Engineering school focuses on gender. Senate passes anti-heterosexism bill. Hitchcock professor [Lee Edelman] returns to Tufts. Studen [Ben Connelly] left speechless in the spotlight. Baseball on four-game slide. Men's lax cruises past greyhounds, Women tame Lyons. Men's tennis goes cold in match with polar bears. V-ball victorious at New Englands.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-09-02; UP055.025.025.00058 (Box 25)
    Matriculation ceremony inaugurates class of 2003. Tufts slides to 29th in rankings. University welcomes highly qualified freshmen. AEPi loses recognition over hazing. Fall sports teams look to repeat success. Jumbo leaves an enormous legacy.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-09-09; UP055.025.025.00059 (Box 25)
    Additional user copy in the Reading Room. Senate surplus now stands at $90,000. Tufts Daily lets commercial business use office, violating school policy. Fire alarms pulled to ward off police. TCU [Tufts Community Union] president optmistic for upcoming term, fall fest. [Larry] Harris to create cabinet. Freshmen adjust to university life. Mountain club president [James Moore] climbs higher. [Rocky] Carzo honored after retirement. Tufts hires new coaches. Sailing team wins nationals. [Bill] Gehling promoted to athletic director. Top athletes bring home hardware. Martha Whiting named women's soccer coach.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-09-16; UP055.025.025.00060 (Box 25)
    Additional user copy in the Reading Room. Hodgdon undergoes second facelift. Tufts alum [Nick Birnback] flees Timor. Students feel pinch of housing shortage. Fletcher student forced out of Iran. Student activities welcomes two new faces. ExCollege courses prove popular. Parisian [Tristan Reed] takes helm of International Club. Season kicks off over the weekend.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-09-23; UP055.025.025.00061 (Box 25)
    Additional user copy in the Reading Room. Judiciary overrules ELBO [Elections Board] decision. New building planned for Tufts muscians. Biology Dept. loses renowned cancer researcher [Shuk-Mei Ho] leaves Tufts for UMASS Worcester citing superior laboratory, not salary. Tufts reaches to the bottom of the ocean. Utility of all-community voicemail messages questioned. English Professor [Michelle Blake Simmons] authors acclaimed novel. Freshman [field hockey] lead jumbos to win. Sailing team finishes strong in meets. Cross country meet a 'tree't for women. Volleyball team bumps record to 9-1. Tufts [men's soccer] 'charges' to win vs. Chargers. [women's] Tennis team bounces back, crushes Smith. No need to 'fight scots' for [women's] soccer team's win.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-10-21; UP055.025.025.00062 (Box 25)
    Additional user copy in the Reading Room. Students campaign for french and spanish major. Club organizers criticize new procedure for reserving rooms. Boston loses reputation as best college town to New York City. Rally focuses on violence against women. [Committee of Student Life] orders new TCUJ [Tufts Community Union Judiciary] hearing. University Chaplain [Scotty Mclennan] pens for all faiths. Sailors struggle in regattas. The verdict is in: Judges win [women's volleyball]. Cross Country teams fall back in New England. Men [soccer] lose in overtime. Tufts [football] falls to Trinity. Jumbos [women's tennis] scrape out 5-4 win vs. Bantams. Soccer team runs streak to 6-0-1.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-10-28; UP055.025.025.00063 (Box 25)
    Additional user copy in the Reading Room. Orchestra policy change criticized. Insects, mice caught in uphill dorm. Rocky Horrow Picture Show comes to Tufts. Senator [Larry Harris] to sit on policy council. English professor's [Andre Dubus III] novel receives national acclaim. Women's soccer falls to rival. Men's cross-counry team wins race at home course. Volleyball ends seven game slide. Tennis team finishes season with solid fourth place finish. Field hockey is lone victor. Pachyderms [crew] finish in the middle of the pack. Jumbos [football] fall in final moments.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-11-11; UP055.025.025.00064 (Box 25)
    CEO [Bernard Gordon] donates $20 million to engineering school. Senate outs courses online, professors cautious. Economics department struggles to meet demand. Survey examines student alcohol use. Latino community reflects on department issues, resignations. Gantcher field house officially opened. Student leader [Kevin Staszowski] acts, dances and males pizza. Men take first in Cross-country. [football] Colby's missed extra points to prevent another loss. Jumbo's [field hockey] romp through ECACs end in finals. Men's soccer extend season. Tufts sailor places fifth in single handed national championship. Volleyball ends tough season.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-11-18; UP055.025.025.00065 (Box 25)
    Capital campaign brings endowment close to $1 billion. Hank Azaria and Eden White recieve light on the hill award. Psychology department welcomes promise of new buildings, labs. Athlete GPA's higher than average, sprts director says. Unexpectedly high use of online course guide surprises senate. Campus leader [Amol Sharma] dedicated to unifying Tufts. Bernstein earmarks $125, 000 for diversity, cultural centers.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-12-03; UP055.025.025.00066 (Box 25)
    Bill Bradley discusses foreign policy with students. ResLife considers shortage solutions. Tufts polls nears launch. Senate sponsers one night assigned seating at Dewick, students urged to try new table. Students register before assigned time, administration seeks fair solution. Democrats member [Anne Maurer] helps bring [Bill] Bradley to Tufts. Winter season storms onto hill. CrossCountry teams impress at nationals.
  - Tufts Observer, 1999-12-05; UP055.025.025.00067 (Box 25)
    E-mail address changes proposed by TCCS [Tufts Computing and Community Services]. CSL [Community on Student Life] postpones appeal hearing. Campus Info System Propsed. Pancake breaksfast planned for Monday. Senate meets town mayors. Community forum lets students voice complaints. History professor [Howard Solomon] examinies the millenium hype. Men's hoops beat beavers in Babson. Women's basketball wins fourth straight in 1999, remains undefeated. Hockey team defeats Chieftans. Men's swimming team has strong start out of the blocks.
  - Tufts Observer, 2000-01-27; UP055.025.025.00068 (Box 25)